Jonathan Anders

St. Augustine, FL | jonathananders99@gmail.com | 206-225-4424

Profile/Portfolio: https://jonathananders99.github.io/Profile-Webpage/

Let's Do This! Determined and eager for the next challenge and ready to make a meaningful difference. A curious and naturally agile thinker who thrives on solving problems. A highly organized and reliable self-starter with a team focus and tenacity to deliver high-quality and timely results. More information on my projects and skills can be found on my <u>website</u>.

Data Analytics and Database Development

A proactive and determined computer science student with a focus on data analytics and database development. From an internship, personal projects, and school projects I gained experienced in creating databases using tools such as **MongoDB** and **Oracle**, integrating databases using **Golang** and **ReactJS**, and analyzing data from databases using **Excel** and **R**. Passionate about using data to inform decision-making and drive business success. Excited to see how **AI** will transform analytics and database development.

EDUCATION

Purdue University (IUPUI) | Indianapolis, IN

- Bachelors Degree in Applied Computer Science (Planned Graduation: May 2023)
- Indiana Wesleyan University | Indianapolis, IN
 - Associates Degree in Business Science (Graduated May 2021)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MongoDB: Created a database based off Twitter with the cluster hosted by AWS.
- **Oracle:** Created a database to store and handle all information necessary for a clothing store inventory system.
- **Google Apps Scripts:** Used google services like Google Apps Script, Google Sheets, Google Drive, Google Calendar, and more to create 3 databases for clients.
- R: Trained ML algorithms like Random Forests and Neural Nets on big data.
- **Golang:** Created a to-do list with front end as ReactJS, and backend as Golang and MongoDB.
- Additional Frameworks and Software: Experience includes but is not limited to: Teradata, Power BI, Java, AWS apps, ReactJS, MySQL, Python, NodeJS, ChatGPT, GitHub, MacOS, SAFe, MSOffice apps. General technical documentation like architecture design documents or user experience design documents.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Purdue University (IUPUI) | Indianapolis, IN

• TA for a computer science course (January 2023 – Present)

Elevance Health (Formerly Anthem BCBS) | Indianapolis, IN

Data Analyst Intern (June 2022 – August 2022)

Part-Time Freelance Programmer | Indianapolis, IN

Database Developer and Junior Website Creator (October 2019 – Present)

Nordstrom Rack | Bellevue, WA & Indianapolis, IN

• Sales Associate and Merchandise Support (July 2018 – January 2020)